<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/OLPC_Activity_Properties" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright> Copyright (C) 2007 Collabora Limited </tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.laptop.Telepathy.ActivityProperties">
    <tp:requires interface="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Connection"/>

    <method name="SetProperties">
      <arg direction="in" name="room" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
          An integer handle representing the room of the activity
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="properties" type="a{sv}">
        <tp:docstring>
          A dictionary mapping properties names to the desired values
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Set the properties of the activity associated to the given room for this connection.
        You have to be the owner of this activity.
      </tp:docstring>
      <tp:possible-errors>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.Disconnected"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.InvalidArgument"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.PermissionDenied"/>
      </tp:possible-errors>
    </method>

    <method name="GetProperties">
      <arg direction="in" name="room" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
          An integer handle for the activity's room to request his properties for
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="out" name="properties" type="a{sv}">
        <tp:docstring>
          A dictionary mapping properties names to their values
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Get the properties of a particular activity.
      </tp:docstring>
      <tp:possible-errors>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.Disconnected"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.InvalidArgument"/>
      </tp:possible-errors>
    </method>

    <signal name="ActivityPropertiesChanged">
      <arg name="room" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
          An integer handle representing the room of the activity
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="properties" type="a{sv}">
        <tp:docstring>
          A dictionary mapping properties names to their new values
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Signal emitted when the properties of an activity are changed.
      </tp:docstring>
    </signal>

    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>An interface on connections to associate OLPC activity properties
    with rooms.</p>

    <p>The following types and names are used to request and set properties:</p>
      <dl>
        <dt>s:color</dt>
        <dd>The color of the activity. Format used is #RRGGBB,#RRGGBB (stroke,fill).</dd>

        <dt>s:name</dt>
        <dd>The name of the activity.</dd>

        <dt>s:type</dt>
        <dd>The type of the activity.</dd>
      </dl>

    </tp:docstring>
  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
