<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Connection_Interface_Renaming" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright> Copyright (C) 2005, 2006 Collabora Limited </tp:copyright>
  <tp:copyright> Copyright (C) 2005, 2006 Nokia Corporation </tp:copyright>
  <tp:copyright> Copyright (C) 2006 INdT </tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Library General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Connection.Interface.Renaming">
    <tp:requires interface="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Connection"/>
    <signal name="Renamed">
      <arg name="original" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
          The handle of the original identifier
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg name="new" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
          The handle of the new identifier
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Emitted when the unique identifier of a contact on the server changes.
      </tp:docstring>
    </signal>
    <method name="RequestRename">
      <arg direction="in" name="name" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>
          The desired identifier
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Request that the users own identifier is changed on the server. Success
        is indicated by a Renamed signal being emitted. A new handle will be
        allocated for the user's new identifier, and remain valid for the
        lifetime of the connection.
      </tp:docstring>
      <tp:possible-errors>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.Disconnected"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.NetworkError"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.NotAvailable"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.InvalidArgument"/>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.PermissionDenied"/>
      </tp:possible-errors>
    </method>
    <tp:docstring>
      An interface on connections to support protocols where the unique
    identifiers of contacts can change. Because handles are immutable,
    this is represented by a pair of handles, that representing the
    old name, and that representing the new one.
    </tp:docstring>
  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
